<resources>
    <string name="app_name">exer2_resurreccion_b4l</string>

    <!--  Title  -->
    <string name="title">Which Disney - Square Enix character are you?</string>

    <!--  Button label  -->
    <string name="start_button">Start</string>

    <!--  Bio  -->
    <string name="bio_sora">
        Sora (ソラ) is the protagonist of the Kingdom Hearts video game series. He is a teenager who originates from the Destiny Islands but obtains the Keyblade, a weapon used to fight creatures known as the Heartless. In order to find the King Mickey, his allies Donald Duck and Goofy recruit him in their journey across various worlds to save them from darkness, as well as find Sora\'s friends. Throughout the games, Sora journeys throughout worlds, interacting with various Disney characters and gains experience with the Keyblade as well as his growth as its wielder.
        \n\nI know the Keyblade didn\'t choose me, and I don\'t care. I\'m proud to be a small part of something bigger - the people it did choose. My friends. They are my power!
        \n- SORA
        \n\nSora is a brave and heroic boy who is extremely loyal to his friends, valuing his friendship with them above all else. He is an optimist and has a strong sense of justice, enabling him to take charge of his group when no one else can. However, he is rather oblivious at times, and is often quick to anger whenever he\'s confused, and is quite childish at times. He is also quite impulsive, as he tends to jump into things without thinking them through beforehand.
        \n\nIn addition, a recurring trait Sora possesses is competitiveness, which has often pitted him against fights with those stronger than him, to the point this has grown to a level of arrogance witnessed in Dream Drop Distance when Sora claims that he is already unbeatable even after the threat of Xehanort has been explained to him. When Sora is captured and nearly converted into a pawn of Xehanort, Sora remembers his humility and learns of his limits that he humbly accepts his failure of the exam.
        \n\nDespite his flaws, Sora is dedicated and kind, making up for his weaknesses with his benevolent and endearing personality. As such, his ability to forgive is incredible along with his ability to connect to others and quickly befriend them. As the series progresses, Sora learns from his past mistakes and becomes less selfish over time as he learns how powerful the heart can be and fight with this in mind.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_riku">
        Riku is the deuteragonist of the Kingdom Hearts video game series. He is a teenager from Destiny Islands and is Sora\'s best friend.
        \n\nOnce we step through, we might not be able to come back. We may never see our parents again. There\'s no turning back. But this may be our only chance. We can\'t let fear stop us! I\'m not afraid of the darkness!
        \n- RIKU
        \n\nRiku\'s personality is as strong as the land for which he was named. He is extremely strong-willed and confident, at times being arrogant. He values his friends deeply and puts protecting them above all else.
        \n\nRiku is extremely competitive, and spent his childhood playing games, play-fighting, and racing with Sora. This competitiveness also made him easy to become jealous, especially during Kingdom Hearts, where he becomes very irked that Sora received the powers of the Keyblade while he did not, though he is not immediately vocal about it. This jealousy led him to behave aggressively to the people most important to him, and he began to act recklessly and harshly in an attempt to prove himself. He loses this childish jealousy streak entirely as he grows older.
        \n\nHe has had an intense curiosity about the world he lives in (and what lies beyond it) ever since he met the foreign Terra as a child. His desire to know more became to consume him somewhat negatively over time. He has no qualms with going through the unknown to earn this knowledge, willingly stepping into a dark portal with an unknown destination simply because he knew it may be his only chance to leave. After he does finally see other worlds, this desire subsides and he finds comfort in his once-restricting island homeworld.
        \n\nAfter the events of Kingdom Hearts, Riku becomes more humble, learning from the reckless mistakes he had made, and seeks to make amends. He becomes much more affable and mellows out. He has learned well from his mistakes in siding with darkness, and becomes wise and well-versed enough to become a Keyblade Master that Yen Sid can rely on.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_kairi">
        Kairi (カイリ) is the tritagonist in the Kingdom Hearts video game series. She is Sora and Riku\'s best friend. Kairi is also a Princess of Heart, one of seven maidens whose hearts hold no darkness but only pure light, and is needed to open the Final Keyhole to Kingdom Hearts.
        \n\nDon\'t ever forget. Wherever you go, I\'m always with you.
        \n- KAIRI TO SORA
        \n\nSora and Riku\'s childhood friend. As one of the seven princesses, she became a target of the forces of darkness, but thankfully Sora and Riku came to the rescue. She is waiting in the Destiny Islands for their safe return.
        \n\nKairi is caring, kindhearted, wise, supportive and outspoken, although she quickly becomes determined and courageous when someone she cares about is in danger. Her sociable, charismatic nature enables her to quickly befriend others comparable to Sora\'s ability. At fourteen years old, Kairi was somewhat brash and bold, but by KH II, she has become more mature, responsible and wise, although she still retains her tomboyishness and bravery.
        \n\nKairi is usually optimistic and upbeat, but she can be rather stubborn sometimes. When faced with a challenge and to protect her friends, Kairi becomes quite loyal and headstrong.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_mickey">
        Mickey plays a major (but not starring) role in the Kingdom Hearts video game series as King Mickey Mouse, the king of Disney Castle, with Minnie Mouse as his Queen. He is also one of the characters most strongly affiliated with light, and fights alongside the main protagonist of the series, Sora, while forming a strong bond with Riku similar to Donald and Goofy\'s bond with Sora. The Japanese versions bring light to Takashi Aoyagi voicing Mickey, while Wayne Allwine reprised his role as Mickey in the English versions up unto the English release of 358/2 Days, after which he passed away; the game was dedicated in his memory. Birth by Sleep is also notably the first full performance of Mickey by Bret Iwan, who has been the official voice of the character since.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_donald">
        In Kingdom Hearts, Donald is the Royal Magician of Disney Castle and the royal assistant for King Mickey and one of the three main non-original Disney protagonist, alongside Mickey and Goofy. As such, his weapon of choice is a Staff. He often provides comic relief more than advancing the plot despite the amount of camera time he has in the series. He is rash and has an aggressive personality, but he is loyal to his friends.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_goofy">
        Goofy appears alongside Donald and Sora in all of the Kingdom Hearts games. Goofy is Captain of the Royal Knights of King Mickey\'s court. He and Disney Castle\'s court magician Donald head out to search for the King and ends up teaming with Sora for the rest of their journey. He is a loyal friend to all he meets, willing to put his life on the line to protect them. Goofy\'s most notable scene in the series is in Kingdom Hearts II, where he is hit in the head by a rock that would have hit Mickey, had Goofy not pushed him out of the way. This caused Sora, Donald, Mickey, and even the player to believe he is dead. Though moments later, Goofy shows up alive and well, saying he \"gets bonked on the head all the time\", a possible nod to his cartoons. Despite being revealed to be alive, this incident is considered the darkest and mature scene in the series. Atypical for most of his depictions, Goofy is considerably wiser than most of the main characters, even Mickey and Riku at times, despite how he comes off in the cartoons. In gameplay, Goofy uses his shield to block and attack enemies, and usually has the highest Defense stat in the series, with the debatable exception of Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_roxas">
        Roxas is one of the main characters of the Disney/Square Enix Kingdom Hearts series, and the protagonist of Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days, as well as the prologue of Kingdom Hearts II.
        \n\nHe is the Nobody of Sora and was Rank XIII within the original Organization XIII. Although Sora\'s heart was restored after his creation, Roxas continued to endure and exist until he was eventually absorbed back into him. However, the knowledge of Roxas would influence Sora to search for a way to revive Roxas. The solution turned out to be by providing a Replica vessel to house Roxas\' newly-formed heart, giving Roxas a life of separate from Sora\'s.
        \n\nYou make a good other.
        \n- ROXAS TO SORA
        \n\nAs he has gained his own heart, Roxas genuinely has his own emotions and personality. Similar to Sora and Ventus, he\'s kind, likable, and friendly. He cares about others and is brave. Roxas is generally more mature and will think rationally before moving forward, unlike the happy-go-lucky Sora. However, Roxas also displays a much more aggressive personality compared to Sora when teased or confused, and can be irritable and impatient. He can also be cocky and arrogant at times.
        \n\nA defining trait to Roxas is his desire to have a life of his own and to be acknowledged as a single being. He spends his entire existence wanting to have friends and to spend time with them like a normal teenager, ever since he first sees children in Twilight Town doing so. Though he will still help people in need, he actually would prefer not to have the keyblade, as it prevents him from living the normal life he wants.
        \n\nHe intensely dislikes being compared to Sora, because he would rather people see him as his own person. He ultimately opts to merge with Sora regardless of all the aforementioned, proving him to be responsible and selfless.
        \n\nRoxas mellows out considerably after he learns of and accepts his fate as Sora\'s nobody.
        \n\nWhen he was first created, he was somewhat \"blank\", not yet understanding life and what it means to have one. He was naive and very curious about his surroundings as his new best friend Axel showed him the world.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_xion">
        Xion is a character originating from Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days and serves as the tritagonist of the game. She is Rank XIV within the original Organization XIII, although she is only a nominal member. Rather than being a nobody, she is an imperfect Replica of Roxas created from Sora\'s leaked memories of Kairi as a failsafe in case both Sora and Roxas proved to be useless to the Organization\'s plans.
        \n\nRoxas, don\'t be sad. I came from you and Sora. I am you…the same way that I\'m Sora. You\'ll forget me, but the memories themselves will never go away. Memories of you and me will always be together…forever inside him.
        \n- XION\'S FINAL WORDS TO ROXAS BEFORE HE FORGETS HER COMPLETELY
        \n\nFirst arriving at Organization XIII, Xion is a shy, secluded individual. When going on a mission with Roxas, Xion begins to open up to him, and later Axel. She does seem to express emotions due to her nature of existence and is always happy to be with her friends. However, she is somewhat emotionally fragile, becoming deeply enraged with the right provocation. After finding out the origins of her existence, she also becomes deeply confused and lost. She has a strong sense of justice and generosity, seen in the way she willingly gave up herself to join with Sora. She resembles Kairi and Naminé in the way that she fights to protect those she has come to care for.
        \n\nXion seems to take an interest in seashells. While Roxas was in a coma when Sora was put to sleep, Xion placed a seashell on his bedside table every day he was asleep. In her nightmare on Destiny Islands, Roxas is in the dream and picks up a shell while whispering her name. After Xion died and returned to Sora, all that was left of her was a single seashell. This is likely a reference to how Kairi also had a liking for seashells too.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_namine">
        Naminé is a major character from Kingdom Hearts. She is the Nobody of Kairi. She was born when Sora became a Heartless, in order to free Kairi\'s heart.
        \n\nRoxas! We will meet again. And then we can talk about everything. I may not know it\'s you, and you may not know it\'s me. But we will meet again. Someday soon. I promise!
        \n- NAMINÉ
        \n\nDue to the unusual nature of her birth, Naminé was born without memories and initially believed she lacked emotions. Because of this, Naminé was an obedient Nobody who acted upon whatever order was given as it was the only guidance she had. She had a timid and introverted personality as a result, and lacked determination, although she seemed to enjoy drawing as an outlet. It was only after she realized that her abilities had horrible consequences on others did she realize that she possesses true emotions, as her actions against Sora and the danger she put him in left her feeling guilty and responsible. She starts deciding for herself because of this guilt by rebelling against Organization XIII, in favor of helping those she had manipulated, leading to her becoming more determined in herself.
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="bio_yensid">
        Master Yen Sid is a powerful sorcerer who made his Disney debut in Fantasia. He appears in Kingdom Hearts II, Kingdom Hearts Birth by Sleep, Kingdom Hearts coded and Kingdom Hearts 3D: Dream Drop Distance as a retired Keyblade Master, renowned for his wisdom and command over the arts of magic; though no longer an active Keyblade Master, he still keeps a close watch on the balance between Light and Darkness. He was once Mickey Mouse\'s master, and taught him everything he knows of magic and the Keyblade. His name is a reverse anagram of \"Disney\", as a tribute to Walt Disney himself.
        \n\nI am no longer a Master. I doffed that mantle.
        \n- YEN SID TO TERRA
        \n\nWhile little is known about his life as a Keyblade Master, the elderly sorcerer is shown to be a rather stern man. In almost every instance, he is shown to be frowning. But beneath his harsh exterior belies a man who strongly believes in his apprentices no matter how much mischief they may get up to, demonstrated by when he expresses annoyance at Mickey for running off with the Star Shard and recklessly getting lost with it, but then forgives Mickey and awards him the title of Master with an encouraging smile.
        \n\nGiven his past status as a Keyblade Master, he is shown to have great knowledge about the properties of the Heart, the Heartless, the Nobodies and the Unversed. It is he who explains the nature of the Nobodies to Sora, Donald and Goofy, and also tells them that as long as darkness exists in one heart, the Heartless will never cease to exist. So powerful and wise he is, that even Terra, Aqua, and Ventus speak to him with utmost respect, despite him not being their master. However, it seems that his associates who are also Keyblade Masters and therefore equal in terms of status, while still referring to him with great respect, doesn\'t call him \"Master\" and merely refers to him as \"Yen Sid\".
        \n
    </string>

    <!--  Content Description  -->
    <string name="disney_image_content_decription">image of logo or randomized character</string>

</resources>
